Jacob Molin

M.Sc. student in Media Tech. and Engineering



+46 73 032 25 79

jacob.cb.molin@gmail.com

<u>iacobmolin.com</u>

<u>LinkedIn</u>

GitHub

PROFILE

Driven, analytical and problem-solving-loving M.Sc. student with a big interest in technology, creation and logical thinking.

With experience in music production, customer service and logistics I have a unique insight in working with and delivering results in teams with many different types of personalities. I'm curious, take initiatives and is always looking on how to improve products and workflows. I'm interested in exploring how technology, with the help of Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning and programming in general, can be used to make life better and more fun for people. I thrive on new challenges and love making people laugh!

EDUCATION

Sep 2017 - (Jun 2022)

M.Sc. in Media Technology and Engineering, Linköping University - Norrköping

Focus on programming and system development. Courses in Machine Learning, Al, Big Data Analytics, Neural Networks and more. Expected graduation June 2022.

Current GPA: 4.13 / 5.0 (Grades are given in U, 3, 4, 5). Currently in my penultimate year.

Bachelor project: In a group of seven where we researched implementation methods and developed an online price comparison service which collects data by web scraping online stores. My focus laid on collecting, comparing and organizing data by writing Python scripts. The project has continued after the course's end (zpeia.com).

Mar 2013 - Jun 2014

Independent Music Production Certificate, UCLA Extension, Westwood CA - USA

Sep 2010 - Jun 2011

Audio Engineering Cert. (Music and Post-Prod.), Musicians Institute, Hollywood CA - USA

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Aug 2019 - Jun 2020

Programming tutor at LiTHeHack, Linköping University - Norrköping

Employed by Linköping University to tutor students in programming during two sessions per week. Students drop in and ask programming-related questions. Most questions

regarded C++, JavaScript and MATLAB.

Aug 2016 - Jul 2018

Location / Production Assistant on film sets, Freelance, Stockholm

Setting up and maintaining film location sets as well as driving actors, crew and equipment to/from location for projects like "Solsidan" (movie) and "Hassel" (TV series).

Aug 2014 - Aug 2017

Audio Engineer / Music Producer, Freelance, Los Angeles / Stockholm

Recording and Audio Engineer for artists like Zara Larsson, Dua Lipa, Rev Run and Jared

Leto. Music producer for artists like Broderick Batts, Taps and Diana Ebe.

Apr 2012 - Nov 2012

Sound / Light Technician, Sports Entertainer, Hotels Viva, Mallorca - Spain

Led sports activities for hotel guests during the day and running sound and light for the stage shows during the night for one season at a hotel on the Spanish island Mallorca.

Mar 2008 - Nov 2009

Restaurant Clerk, McDonald's, Täby

Full-time periodically and part-time during studies.

2006 - Present

Various summer and part time jobs, Stockholm / Norrköping

Like store clerk at Hemköp (present), outdoor cinema technician, janitor and

warehouse worker.

COMMISSIONS OF TRUST

May 2020 – May 2021 Auditor, NAFFI (Norrköping's Academic Sports Association), Norrköping

As one of two auditors, being responsible for auditing the accounting and financial

situation of NAFFI for the academic year 2019/2020.

May 2018 – May 2019 Chairman, NAFFI (Norrköping's Academic Sports Association), Norrköping

I was responsible for running board meetings and ultimately responsible for the weekly

and overall operations.

PROJECTS IN AND OUT OF SCHOOL

Nov 2020 – Dec 2020 Project in the course "Machine Learning for Social Media", Linköping University

Just about to start a group project in Machine Learning using data from social media.

Oct 2020 – Nov 2020 Resume and portfolio website: jacobmolin.com, Own initiative

Developed my own resume and portfolio website to learn more about web development!

Implemented with React and Next.js.

Sep 2019 – Nov 2019 VizWiz - Project in the course "Audio Physics", Linköping University

Developed, in a group of three, an online frequency spectrum analyzer with JavaScript

and React. Go to jacobmolin.com/portfolio for link to demo and GitHub repo.

Oct 2018 – Jan 2019 diatot - Project in the course "Communication and User Interface (UI)", Linköping University

With focus on the UI, the group of four developed a mobile phone adapted website for diabetics to calculate a meal dose of insulin. The goal was to simplify the everyday life of diabetics by letting them spend less time managing their disease. Implemented using JavaScript and React. Go to jacobmolin.com/portfolio for link to demo and GitHub repo.

INTERNSHIPS

2011 – 2014 Recording / Audio Engineer intern, Los Angeles

Various recording / audio engineer internships in professional studios with international producers and songwriters like Al Shux (Jay-Z, Alicia Keys) and David Jost (Selena Gomez, Tokio Hotel). Among many things, I recorded A-list artists, built a vocal booth and rewired

an entire studio.

SKILLS

Language Programming

Swedish (Native) ••••• JavaScript •••• Python •••• C++ •••• English •••• MATLAB •••• Git •••• Java

PERSONAL

I'm originally from Stockholm, but now I live and study in Norrköping. I spent four years in Los Angeles studying and working in music recording and production, where I had the opportunity to work with major artists, producers and songwriters. In the end I decided that I wanted to pursue a career within programming and technology development, which has been a big interest for me since I was a kid. My biggest passion of all is to learn new things, not only within technology and programming, but also about things like other cultures or how to run a business. In my spare time I love playing music, exercising, travelling, experiencing nature, listen to podcasts and having a great time with my friends.

I hope we'll have the chance to meet soon!